BEEN KIM

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests include making human-understandable machine learning models and algorithms. These provide powerful and intuitive explanations to human users. The goal is to leverage both data and human experts' knowledge by establishing a feedback loop between domain experts and machine learning models. My general approach includes designing Bayesian generative models that can provide intuitive explanations without sacrificing predictive accuracy, and accelerating inference algorithms by using logic-informed prior.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Affiliate Faculty 2015 - Present

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Washington, WA, USA

Research Scientist 2015 - Present

Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence, WA, USA

Software Engineer 2010 - 2012

MathWorks, MA, USA

Development of a new framework to interface MATLAB with C/C++

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA, USA

2012 - 2015 Areas of Concentration: Interpretable and Interactive Machine Learning Advisor: Julie Shah

Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL) Committee: Julie Shah (Chair), Cynthia Rudin and Randall Davis

Cumulative GPA: 4.00/4.00

M.Sc., Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA, USA 2007 - 2010

Advisor: John Leonard Thesis: Multiple Relative Pose Graphs for Cooperative Mapping

Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL)

Cumulative GPA: 4.00/4.00

B.Sc., Seoul National University, Korea 2003-2007

Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Summa Cum Laude

Cumulative GPA: 4.02/4.30

PUBLICATIONS

Examples are not Enough, Learn to Criticize! Criticism for Interpretable Machine Learning 2016

Author: B. Kim*, R. Khanna*, S. Koyejo*

Conference: Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS), Oral presentation

Mind the Gap: A Generative Approach to Interpretable Feature Selection and Extraction 2015

Author: B. Kim, F. Doshi-Velez, J. Shah

Conference: Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS)

Scalable and interpretable data representation for high-dimensional complex data 2015

Author: B. Kim, K. Patel, A. Rostamizadeh, J. Shah

Conference: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)

Inferring Team Task Plans from Human Meetings: A Generative Modeling Approach with Logic-**Based Prior** 2014

Author: B. Kim. C. Chacha, J. Shah

Journal: Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research (JAIR)

Bayesian Case Model: A Generative Approach for Case-Based Reasoning and Prototype Classi-

fication 2014

Author: B. Kim, C. Rudin and J. Shah

Conference: Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) Learning about meetings 2014 Author: **B. Kim** and C. Rudin Journal: Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery (DMKD) Human-inspired Techniques for Human-Machine Team Planning (AAAI Tech Report) 2013 Author: J. Shah. B.Kim and S. Nikolaidis Inferring Robot Task Plans from Human Team Meetings: A Generative Modeling Approach with **Logic-Based Prior** 2013 Author: B. Kim, C. Chacha, J. Shah Conference: Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Quantitative Estimation of the Strength of Agreements in Goal-Oriented Meetings 2013 Author: B. Kim, L. Bush, J. Shah Conference: International Multi-Disciplinary Conference on Cognitive Methods in Situation Awareness and Decision Support (CogSIMA) Multiple Relative Pose Graphs for Robust Cooperative Mapping 2010 Author: B. Kim, M. Kaess, L. Fletcher, J. Leonard, A. Bachrach, N. Roy and S. Teller Conference: International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2010

INVITED TALKS

Machine learning seminar, University of Washington	Jan. 2017
University of Cambridge	July. 2016
Lunch Seminar Series, California Institute of Technology	April 2016
Computer Science Engineering Women's Research Day, University of Washington	Jan. 2016
Keynote speech at WiML at NIPS	Dec. 2015
Data/Analytics/Machine Learning MeetUp, Seattle WA	Nov. 2015
Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA	Oct. 2015
University of Washington, WA	Oct. 2015
IBM Thomas J. Watson Research Center, NY	Jan. 2015
Google Research NYC, NY	July 2014
Boston university, MA	June 2014

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Interpretable Models and Interactive Machine Learning (See SELECTED PRESS) 2012 - present

- Developing Bayesian generative models that provide intuitive explanations to users by leveraging case-based reasoning
- Building general interpretable machine learning framework
- Designing machine learning methods that can incorporate human experts' domain knowledge

Logic-based Informative Prior for Bayesian Generative Models

2012 - 2013

- Integrated a logic-based tool Planning Domain Definition Language (PDDL) plan validator (logic based) with a Bayesian generative modeling framework
- Showed significant improvements inferring the content of human team planning conversation data from rescue missions

Data Mining to Learn about Meetings (See SELECTED PRESS)

2012 - 2013

 Performed extensive data mining using discrete optimization to discover quintessential patterns in meetings

Multi-robot Localization and Mapping

2008 -2010

- Developed a multi-robot navigation algorithm that can simultaneously perform localization and mapping using probabilistic modeling
- Demonstrated on an autonomous multi-robot system providing persistent situational awareness for an autonomous forklift and a guide robot

INTERNSHIPS

INTERNSHIPS	
Google Research, NY, USA Research Intern at Machine Learning API team	Summer 2014
Development of Bayesian Interpretable models and result visualization Bain & Company, Seoul, Republic of Korea Consulting Research Assistant	Summer 2007
Optimization of airline routes; Data search, organization and analysis iTalknews, CA, USA Marketing Assistant User interface design; Website traffic analysis; Website promotion project organizer	Winter 2005
SELECTED PRESS	
Talking Machines: Real Human Actions and Women in Machine Learning Computers that teach by example MIT news	2016 2014
At Work: Just Say 'Yeah' Wall Street Journal	2013
How To Win Over Co-Workers And Influence Meetings: Use These 3 Words Forbes	2013
5 Important Words to Say in Every Business Meeting Yahoo news	2013
Researchers Discover the Key to Persuasion ABC news	2013
TEACHING AND MENTORING EXPERIENCE	
Committee member Nan-Chen Chen, PhD student at University of Washington	2015
Real-time Systems and Software Department of Aeronautics and Astronautics, MIT Teaching Assistant	Spring 2013
Evaluation: 6.7/7.0 Mentoring undergraduate research students (UROP) at MIT Janelle Mansfield: Meeting data analysis Caleb ChaCha: Web-based experiment framework development and experiment	2012-current 2012 2012
(co-author on AAAI 13 and JAIR papers) Alex Lednev: Visualizing data project	2012
Brittney Johnson: Experiment interface design (co-author on a paper in submission)	2014
PROFESSIONAL SERVICE	
Area chair, Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) Program committee, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) Co-organizer, Interpretability for complex systems workshop at NIPS Co-organizer, Interpretability for machine learning workshop at ICML Program committee, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Board member, Women in Machine Learning Worshop Reviewer, Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) Program committee, International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	2017 2017 2016 2016 2017 2015-present 2016
nominated for outstanding PC Program committee, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)	2016 2016
Machine Learning track Committee member International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)	2015

AAAI Reviewer	2014-2015
Reviewer, International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2012-2015
Reviewer, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)	2012-2015
Honors	
AAAI Travel Award Seattle, WA, USA	2013
NIPS WiML Travel Award Lake Tahoe, Nevada, USA	2012
CogSIMA Travel Award San Diego, CA, USA	2012
Vicki Kerrebrock Award MIT, MA, USA	2009
Awarded to Graduate Association of Aero. Astro., MIT	
Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Scholarship 50K per year for 2 years, Korea	2007-2009
Best Thesis Presentation Seoul National University, Korea	2007
National Science and Engineering Scholarship Korea	2003-2006
Robot Design and Manufacturing Contest Second Place, Seoul National University, Ko	rea 2005
Academic Excellence Scholarship Seo-Hyun High School, Korea	2000-2003

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Python, Java, MATLAB, Simulink **Operating Systems**: Linux, Windows, Mac OS

PUBLIC SERVICE

President Korean Aero. Astro. Association, MIT	2010 - 2011
International Student Chair Graduate Association of Aero. Astro., MIT	2007 - 2008
08 Graduate Student Orientation Organizer Graduate Student Council, MIT	2008
Kwan-jung Scholarship Vice President Kwan-jung Educational Institute, Korea	2007 - 2009
Staff, Buddy Program for International Student Seoul National University, Korea	2006 - 2007
Volunteer: Teacher and Mentor Dream Tree Free School, NGO for Free Education, Korea	a 2003

REFERENCES

provided upon request.